Sai Kiran Vepamani

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - II · FULL STACK DEVELOPER

□ +91 9493922218 | ■ vepamanisaikiran@gmail.com | ★ vepamanisaikiran.github.io/portfolio | ☑ vepamanisaikiran | ் saikiranvepamani

Skills_

Programming Python · Java · Scala · C++/C · MySQL

ML libraries OpenCV · Numpy · Pandas · Matplotlib · Scikit-learn · Tensorflow · Pytorch

Web/Media HTML/CSS/Javascript/JQuery · Bootstrap · Abode Illustrator

Frameworks/Tools Diango · Angular 7 · Wso2 · Git · Jenkins · Bash · Flutter · Wordpress · Postman · Jira · Filezilla · Flask

About me

Current Software Engineer - II at HashedIn by Deloitte. 2+ years of experience specializing in back-end development and Front end development. Interested in devising a better solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience_

Zapcom Solutions

Bangalore, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Feb. 2020 - July 2021

• Written RestAPI using python in django drf and migrated database from kinvey to django models

- Implemted FCM push notification and celery task in python
- · Collected, defined, and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- · Created and Maintained AWS instances for daily review extractions along with the scoring of reviews using spacy
- constructed powerful Content Management service interface for handling 1000+ client devices in WSO2.
- Redesigned and Edited 70% of UI controlling user flow architecture.
- · Written Automation test script in Python using selenium by saving 35% manual testing effort for performance and load testing.
- Collaborated on all stages of the systems development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Pitched in to assist senior developers to meet pressing deadlines during under-staffed periods
- · Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs, and enhancements.
- · Took concepts and produced design mockups and prototypes to strengthen designs, enhance user experiences
- Created eye catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms to Strengthened company brand and identity.

Zapcom Solutions Bangalore, India

FULL STACK INTERN

Jan. 2019 - Jan. 2020

- Completed full redesigns of existing zapcom portal to improve navigation, enhance visuals and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS, Cross-browser compatibility and responsive website.
- Strengthened search engine rankings from 5th place to 1st place using SEO techniques.
- Designed implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement.
- Used places 365 data sets to generate a model for the scene classification of an image.
- Accelerated scraping code in java with selenium and python with scrapy to get 1000+ customer reviews of 540+ client hotels and store in the database from all the major review OT's for building better customer experience.
- Expedited code in python to get reviews from the Facebook page with the help developer API of 100+ clients hotels.

Education

JNTUA(Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Anantapuramu)

Ananthapur, India

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering with 7.74 GPA

Aug. 2015 - May. 2019

- Won prize in a hackathon for designing feedback management system for JNTUA college 2019
- Received Outstanding Performance award in CodersBit 2018

Projects

- Devised 60% of JNTUACEA website for better user interface and usability.
- Created an online book repository for college consists of 100+ open source books according to the curriculum available only in the college network.
- · Led a team of 3 members for hackathon competition and won the prize for building the best feedback management system.
- Revamped portfolio in the flutter framework from an existing GitHub repository.